Tomlin:
So the implication here is that
you need a lot of preliminary work. It's
not easy.
It's a very advanced practice, and you need a
lot of contemplation and meditation
before this. And we're going to do some. Let's do
an hour.
So get ready to meditate.
Grandfather is going to guide you in a meditation, a
short meditation.
Those in Vietnam call me Oncoy, which
means the wise one, I think,
or grandfather.
We're going to do about 10 minutes.
When you meditate in a group,
you have a greater obligation to
turn off your cell phone, to be
silent.
You have to turn off your cell phone; your
nose might be running.
Here we go.
This week, I want you to
try a new way of
starting a meditation, which is 100
breaths. I do
n't know if I've gotten
more distracted with age, but 10
breaths don't work;
100 do.
So that's it.
Try to count 100 breaths. You
can continue if you get lost. So
try to remember where you are. Okay.
Let's always count
breaths. The exhalation is the
first half, and the inhalation is the
second.
Now, I'd like you to think about
an interaction you had with someone,
probably yesterday,
someone with whom  You spent half an hour in
the last few days.
Try to pick one of those
interactions with another person, at
least half an hour that you spent together.
Try to remember what you were
looking for in that interaction.
I spent the last few days with my wife
taking care of my mom who had a
heart attack, and I spent a lot of time with
Veronica. I think I was
hoping to work on the text. It was kind of in the
back of
my mind. What
were you thinking when you were
with this person? What did you
want to do during that time?
And
what do you think the other
person wanted to be during that time,
based on what you were talking about, based on what you
were doing?
What do you guess they
most wanted to do while they were
together? What was going on in their mind? What would they have
enjoyed doing
during that time?
But my wife at that time
was really focused on helping my
mom,
and she has a list of three people she's
helping. I think she would have liked us to
really focus on that
time. You
could sacrifice what you wanted to do
and just do what the
other person wanted to be.
And that probably wouldn't be sustainable. You
probably would
n't be able to keep doing that.  That, and you
also have important things to
do, things you'd like to do,
and they have things they'd like to
do.
So there
might be a third alternative.
And couples
are constantly thinking of
a third option.
I know what my wife would like to do today. I
know what I'd like to do today.
And is there a
third, clever, creative,
innovative way
between the two of us that we can do what we
want
and be together and still be
interacting and still spend time
together? Is there a way we
can both
do what we want
individually,
create a third possibility
for our relationship or our
interaction where, in a way, we both
do better at the same time
than if we weren't together? Is there a
way I
can work on the translation
and a way we could be
serving my mother
and my wife's other clients? Is
there a way we can
both do it at the same time?
We have the same rights to do what we
want to do.
And is there a super creative way we
can help each other
do what we both want to do and
do it better
than if we tried to do what we
want to do individually
or at the expense of other people?
And this is it.  The lifestyle
of a Body Sacro is
not about sacrificing what they want to
do; they
are not selfishly only doing
what they want to do. They are
finding creative ways
in which everyone can get what they
want at the same time.
So think about this
interaction and try to think of a
third, a third alternative between
those two options, a
way in which you could have
accomplished
what you both wanted
during the same day.
So what my wife and I did was
set aside some time in the morning.
She loves to walk; we were in
California, and she loves to walk by
the ocean.
So she would go for a walk.
We made a deal,
and she could be
preparing
her to-do list for
the day,
contemplating what she was going to do during the
day. And during that time,
I would work on the big translation. And
then we would get together at the
end of the morning
and combine our views.
She has a list of people she would like us to
help, and I have my own list. So we
spent a few minutes
combining our views
and figuring out a way we could
both do it during the day.
Try to think if  There's a way
you could have done that with this
person in your interaction this week. It's
called punzumbo. It's
a super creative way,
a super creative middle ground between
doing only what they want and
doing only what you want. There's
a super creative way to do both,
and neither person has to
sacrifice their
goals. Both people's goals for that
day are equally important. Okay,
slowly. Open your eyes. Throw yourself down.
And I think if you're like me, I
remember when I first came
to Diamond Monkey, I had 80 students in
New York, and we came here to learn the
Diamond Way together.
They did seven years of preparation in
New York, and then we did seven
years of the Diamond Way here, and we all
graduated.
Many people did three-year retreats.
Now there are 200,000 students
worldwide.
So there are 200,000 students, and there are
like 15 organizations.
And there are like 200,000 students.
So I have these demands on my
time. It might have gone from 80 to
200,000, and the demands on my time are
like, that's the amount of increase,
and I can't do it all.  What do I do with my
wife? I don't
try to do what
200,000 people would want, like I did
for 80 people.
Fortunately, I have some of
those people from the 80s, and I
ask them, "Could we chat for an hour?"
No, things have changed. By the way, I'm going to
spend time with them, and I always have time in a
way, but you ca
n't accommodate 200,000 people
like you did 80. It's not possible. I
'm not saying you should go crazy and
try to give an hour to 200,000
people. We calculated it the other day; it would take
16 years. Today's calculation
would take 16.6 years or something like that. It's
not about that. It's not about
managing your time
more cleverly. Time is also empty.
Time can also be
bent and shortened. There it is, proven
with
Mercury. Excuse me, the Mercury line
on Earth bends with gravity, and
the sun can be verified, as Einstein
predicted,
that the light from
Mercury... The planet Mercury seems to slow down
when it passes
by the sun.  And time stops,
time goes slower, time is a
circle, space is curved, and it takes longer
than light to reach
us because it has to pass through the
sun. So it means you're traveling
to the past when you see the planet Mercury
through the telescope. Literally,
you're traveling to the past, you're taking
a time trip.
And the new web telescope
is more the case that you can be in the
past, you can observe the past
directly as it's happening.
So
the method of the Bodychita to accommodate
all people equally
has to do with the emptiness of time
and space. Okay,
we find time, we create time,
and I almost said a bad word, and we
modify space, and we can serve
more people. So the two types of
Bodychita, the two types of Bodychita
help each other. It's impossible for me in
normal time and space to do what I
used to do, and it's impossible to accommodate a
thousand people like I'm doing with my wife
this week,
unless I can work with
emptiness. Okay, so you need that
tool. In my opinion,
the reason this
discussion started, by saying that the fake Bodychita
was...  Implying that you have to use the
bodychita in a superb way too, or you
can never serve people
equitably. You can't accommodate
countless beings, the desires of
countless beings, for the same amount of time
unless you can modify time.
And you'll get
better, and you'll keep improving with
this. First, the desire has to be
there to help
hundreds of thousands of people. First,
the desire has to be there, and that
need is what
drives you to do it. If you have that hunger,
if you have that desire to serve hundreds of
thousands of people, you'll find a
way because the human mind, the
capacity of the human mind, your
capacity to serve others is truly infinite.
You really have an infinite capacity. You
simply have to strive to
achieve it. Okay, very good. Let's talk more
about this.